Peter Thach

Leader/Engineer/Data Analyst/ITGuru/

tthach830@gmail.com

Summary

I am a seasoned technical professional with over 10 years with a proven high degree of experience in analyzing and optimizing Key Performance Metrics for AT&T,T-Mobile, and Sprint network. I am result driven with ability to adapt and earn quickly. I have a strong passion for utilizing BI tools to find root causes and opportunities. I have also founded 2 startups: TTConsulting and Holyhost focusing on providing turn-key IT software/services in the non-profit sector. I have also worked at Outreach as a program manager managing students from Berkeley and Santa Clara University to develop the first live traffic app (Intelligent Transporation System) utilizing data from smartphone and traffic sensors. Furthermore, with my IT/ME background, I helped NASA Research developed the first online collaboration tools for designing student spacecraft. Specialties: Optimization/Analysis of KPI/ Metrics, Design of Wireless Systems, IT, SQL, DB, Unix Scripting

Experience

RF Engineer/Data Analyst at AT&T Mobility January 2010 - Present (5 years 6 months)

As RF Support Engineer: Supported Northern California market from engineers to AVP: Coordinated and led multiple teams (Sales, C&E, RAN) to help deliver monthly, quarterly, annual reports to executives. Analyzed market-wide offenders, benchmark data, and provide solutions to help drive KPIs. Ad-hoc support included Tools, GWS, IT Network Troubleshooting, and website/ database design & implementation, As Optimization RF engineer: Helped drive improvement to the network to meet capacity/coverage need and attained best in class in network accessibility and retainability for our customers. Simulated & studied RF propagation using Atoll, drive test data, and KPI to determine coverage, interference, or pilot pollution. Analyzed KPIs to help fund capital projects (NSB, MODs, DAS) and non-capital (optimization) solutions. Developed and Helped local market use new Unix tools saving company over \$100K/year Performed and optimized DAS system at Fortune 100 companies (Genetech, Visa, Oracle) Use amos/moshell to script and make batch changes to the network. Market tool POCand help assess engineers/market need for tools to improve their work. Market SON Expert using Intucell SON tool responsible for SON issue and resolution and training engineers. Retuned Nortel GSM sites for spectrum clearing and interference resolution Trained engineers how to manage Nortel network Managed customer complaints and enterprise escalations. Filed FCC complaints for LTE interference issue Approved NSB/MOD/DAS Designs AT&T LTE Bronze & Silver Certified

LCC Principal RF Engineering Consultant at AT&T March 2009 - September 2009 (7 months)

- Responsible for the optimization and support for Tulsa & OKC team * Performed optimization for Nortel V17 AT&T network in OKC & TULSA improving network VRET from 96.2% to 96.9% and V_ACC from 96.1% to 97.2% Performed CallPathTrace and Parameter Audits Recommended changes to minimize key network performance metrics and hardware issues.
- Queried SQL Databases using TOAD, PL/SQL Dev, MSQuery Developed Excel/Access
 Performance Tools to identify problem sites on an hourly basis instead of daily basis Developed
 MS Access Adjacent Nbr Tool to look at neighbor HO relation stat

TekSystems RF Engineering Consultant at T-Mobile December 2007 - February 2009 (1 year 3 months)

Managed and consulted RF engineering activities supporting the design, performance and optimization of existing and new GSM/UMTS sites. Led design team to achieve 50 new sites within last 6 months of 2008 and 60 new rings. Performed site survey for indoor/outdoor solutions. Trained new contractors on design tools, principles, and optimization of new sites. Developed and implemented processes that helped select the best candidate for new sites Identified and assessed 2G to 3G site upgrades (antennae, lines, TMA) Redlined and Approved Construction Drawings (CD) Evaluated and approved PRF & SCIP candidates, site-walk, and zoning Evaluated Antennae and TMA selection to support both GSM/UMTS technology Designed 50 new rings based on customer needs and local market feedback Performed pre/final AM/FAA/FCC filing for regulatory compliances Reviewed and approved Frequency-Plannin before bringing new sites on-air. Performed site design/optimization using various tools: ASSET, xPM, Mapinfo, Excel, OptPCS Recommended add/remove nbrs, add/remove TRXs, and tilts Successfully turned up sites with high MOU/DROP and GoS Analyzed traffic and recommended radio add for special events

TekSystems RF Engineering Consultant at Sprint Nextel December 2006 - December 2007 (1 year 1 month)

- Responsible for performing RF engineering activities supporting the design, development and optimization of Sprint/iDEN network. Helped the migration of 800 network to 900 network
- Troubleshoot and resolve 900 interferences using Spectrum Analyzer and worked with other operators to resolve external interferences Performed Market-wide Link Budget and Wizard database update Queried SQL databases for Performance and Asset management tools Developed and implemented Hourly Worst Offender Excel tools used by Austin RF Engineers Performed drive test, noise floor test, white band, peak band tests for 900MHZ sites
- Troubleshoot weekly top offenders and recommending changes. Performed propagation using PlanetEV for CDMA network and Wizard for iDEN network Performed CW testing and Model Tuning for iDEN and CDMA network Performed Site Survey and optimization (ant tilt and parameter changes)

TNS RF Engineering Consultant at Nortel Networks

December 2005 - November 2006 (1 year)

Market Prime - Performed optimization for Dobson GSM wireless network in AZ,TX,OK, MS containing 844 cell sites. Reduced overall dropped calls and improved end-user customer's experience.
 Pulled network performance metrics & site stat using PrOptima, Nortel Eperf, CPT, OMC-R.
 Checked for handover, coverage, and interference using TEMS
 Link Budget Neighbor analysis & optimization, parameter optimization, frequency planning and interference analysis
 Prepared agenda for daily meeting with our client
 Analyzed daily and weekly performance trends
 recommended parameter changes to minimize key network performance metrics
 Prepared weekly "system improvements" reports to management team.
 Analyzed and post process TEMS optimization drive data

Sr. Application Engineering Consultant at CADVision

February 2005 - December 2005 (11 months)

Assessed, Developed, Implemented and Supported enterprise solution to improve company's workflow through Autodesk PLM software.
 Autodesk ATC Instructor – trained over 200 students both onsite and offsite.
 Worked with sales person to develop quarterly plan and to schedule onsite demonstration of product and training
 Provided remote(webex) and onsite technical support

Volunteer Experience

Developed online collaboration rocket design tool for students at NASA Ames Research Center April 2003 - May 2004 (1 year 2 months)

Developed online rocket design tool for students to collaborate from around the world.

Languages

Vietnamese

Skills & Expertise

Wireless

GSM

Network Design

Communications Audits

Network Performance

RF Engineering

Network Optimization

LTE

Actix

WiMAX

3G

CDMA

4G

RF

UMTS

Taken LTE Courses by Ericsson & Award

Solutions

Certified SON Expert (Intucell)

LTE Bronze Certified

Unix Shell Scripting

Business Objects

SQL Query

MapInfo

Education

San Jose State University

BS, Mechanical Engineering minor in Computer Science and EE, 1998 - 2004

Activities and Societies: 6/02-12/03 President of American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) SJSU ASME & IEEE Member Designed and Competed in the 2004 Human Powered Vehicle Competition Member of Campus Crusade for Christ Part of NASA AMES & SJSU Aerospace Engineer Space Vehicle Online Design Project

Interests

Sand Volleyball, Learning and changing the world

Peter Thach

Leader/Engineer/Data Analyst/ITGuru/

tthach830@gmail.com



1 person has recommended Peter

"When Peter was a consultant at Sprint, he was assigned to provide supports for me to complete a system retune, the retune was pushed ahead of schedule due to some unforeseen circumstances, we had to work over the weekend, and it was rather intense and stressful...yet, Peter demonstrated outstanding work ethics and quickly grasped the complex rebanding concepts and hit the ground running - the retune was very successful and our network achieved all time best. Peter has excellent computer skills including but not limited to MS Access, VB and various RF prediction tools. Peter is also a team player, and a great communicator, and would be an asset for any wireless company that hires him."

— Douglas Tek Ho, worked directly with Peter

Contact Peter on LinkedIn